Finding Aid for Fargo Engineering Company records, 1897-1951
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Fargo Engineering Company records 1897-1951, 1910-1930
Fargo Engineering Company.
11 linear feet
9543 Bb 2
Company established by William G. Fargo of Jackson, Michigan, a pioneer in hydroelectric engineering. The company specialized in providing civil engineering design, construction, and consultation services for various power plant projects and dams mainly in Michigan but also in Connecticut, Iowa, Nebraska, Texas, and Wisconsin. The record group consists of two series: Job Files and Office Files. The Job Files series consists of the following subseries: Alphabetical Cross Index of Jobs, Visual Materials, Design Reports and Site Specific Materials, and Engineering Field Notes. The Office Files series includes business correspondence of William G. Fargo for the period of 1897 to 1905 and relating in part to the construction of an interurban/electric trolley system for Jackson, Michigan. Office Files also includes a folder of office specifications, contracts and test procedures and a folder of published promotional sales material.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by Julian R. Ward, Vice President of Brown & Root, Inc., Houston, Texas (donor no. 8364 ) in April, 1995.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Fargo Engineering Company of Jackson, Michigan was the outgrowth of the engineering business started in 1895 by William G. Fargo, a pioneer in hydroelectric engineering. In 1888, Fargo opened an office in Jackson that performed general mapping and surveying work. In 1893 he published a detailed property map of Jackson, and in 1895, he began making surveys of Michigan rivers for water power developments. This work resulted in much of the electric power development in Michigan by Consumers Power Company. In 1913 William G. Fargo started the Fargo Engineering Company, which was incorporated in 1921.
From 1900 until his retirement in 1925, Fargo and his company provided civil engineering design and construction supervision services in connection with power plants and railways for the Michigan companies that later merged to form the Commonwealth and Southern Corporation. The company carried out hydraulic investigations of many Michigan rivers and did experimental engineering work in hydro-power. In particular, Fargo Engineering did much experimental work in spillway design incorporating "Tainter" gates (a form of radial gate adapted to timber construction which had been patented by Jeremiah B. Tainter of Menomonie, Wisconsin), evaporation studies in connection with reservoirs, and investigation of possible dam sites in Michigan and elsewhere. The company, in addition, made topographic surveys of most of the rivers in Michigan's Lower Peninsula and specialized in dams built on soil foundations. During this period, the company completed sixty-one hydroelectric plants and nine major power steam plants in twenty-nine states. The company also designed high tension transmission lines, power substations and office and factory buildings.
Some of the more important hydroelectric and steam power generating plants the Fargo Company built in Michigan while Fargo was with the firm are the Mio, Alcona, Loud, Five Channels, Cooke and Foote plants on the AuSable River, the Webber on the Grand River, the Ceresco, Plainwell, Otsego and Trowbridge plants on the Kalamazoo River, and the Junction plant on the Manistee River. In addition to Jackson, steam plants bearing the Fargo imprint are at Battle Creek, Kalamazoo, Grand Rapids and Flint.
While Fargo Engineering Company was largely concerned with the design of power plants in Michigan, it also provided design, construction and consulting services for other Midwestern power syndicates, including: the Indiana and Michigan Electric Company of South Bend, Indiana, the Iowa Railway and Light Company of Cedar Rapids, Iowa, and the Wisconsin-Minnesota Light and Power Company. Additionally, Fargo Engineering supervised construction of several hydro-electric sites in New England and designed five plants with automatic flood gates on the Guadalupe River of Texas for Texas Power Corporation and Texas Hydro-electric Corporations.
Born in Jackson on December 6, 1867, William G. Fargo was a nationally known civil engineer, city planner and naturalist. In addition to his work in hydroelectric power construction, Fargo was an early developer of the city of Jackson and was considered the "father" of the city zoning ordinance. William Fargo remained active in zoning and city development until 1948, well past his 1925 retirement from Fargo Engineering Company. A noted scientist, he was an honorary curator of birds and paleozoology at the University of Michigan Museum of paleontology and zoology and contributed substantially to the museum's bird specimen collection. He remained unmarried throughout his lifetime and died at the age of 89 on February 2, 1957.
The records of the Fargo Engineering Company consists design reports, field notes, and photographs of various dam an power plant construction projects as well as office files, primarily correspondence. The records consist of eleven linear feet of materials dating from 1897 to 1951 with the bulk of the documents dating from 1910 to 1930. The record group has been divided into two series: Job Files and Office Files.
Subjects:
Fargo Engineering Company.; Civil engineering--Michigan.; Dams--Connecticut--Design and construction.; Dams--Iowa--Design and construction.; Dams--Michigan--Design and construction.; Dams--Nebraska--Design and construction.; Dams--Texas--Design and construction.; Dams--Wisconsin--Design and construction.; Dams--Surveying.; Fargo, William G., 1867-1957.; Hydroelectric power plants--Connecticut.; Hydroelectric power plants--Iowa.; Hydroelectric power plants--Michigan.; Hydroelectric power plants--Nebraska.; Hydroelectric power plants--Texas.; Hydroelectric power plants--Wisconsin.; Jackson (Mich.); River engineering--Michigan.; Electric railroads.; Street-railroads--Michigan--Jackson.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Fargo Engineering Company.; Dams--Connecticut.; Dams--Iowa.; Dams--Michigan.; Dams--Nebraska.; Dams--Wisconsin.; Dams--Texas.; Power plants--Iowa.; Power plants--Michigan.; Power plants--Nebraska.; Power plants--Wisconsin.; Power plants--Texas.; Power plants--Connecticut.; Au Sable River (Mich.); Manistee River (Mich.); Muskegon River (Mich.); Thornapple River (Mich.); Grand River (Mich.); Guadalupe River (Tex.); Flambeau River (Wis.); Chippewa River (Wis.); Cedar Rapids (Iowa); Croton (Mich.); Waterloo (Iowa); Rivers.; Laborers.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Job Files
  The Job Files series consists of the following subseries: Alphabetical Cross Index Of Jobs, Visual Materials, Design Reports And Site Specific Materials, and Engineering Field Notes.
  - Alphabetical Cross Index Of Jobs (Box 1)
    The Alphabetical Cross Index Of Jobs subseries (1 bound volume) cross-indexes most Fargo Engineering Company jobs by name to alternate names, location (according to city, associated river, or both), Fargo job number, and client company. When used in conjunction with this finding aid, the researcher will find this document to be a useful reference tool.
  - Visual Materials
    The Visual Materials subseries (6.5 linear feet) consists mainly of single site photograph albums, arranged alphabetically by state (Connecticut, Iowa, Michigan, Nebraska, Texas, and Wisconsin). These albums are further arranged alphabetically by construction site within the appropriate state. The albums document various hydroelectric, power plant, and dam construction projects undertaken by Fargo Engineering Company mainly in the period from 1906 to 1940. Within the Wisconsin grouping, however, there are four photograph albums which date from 1949 to 1951. The Michigan grouping is the largest, and contains extensive visual documentation of many large lower peninsula power projects undertaken between 1905 and 1937. Individual photographs in the albums have been well documented by Fargo Engineering, with most containing a job number and (or) date on each print. An attempt has been made in this finding aid to supply a location, Fargo job number, and surrounding dates for each album. The researcher can discover alternate names and the client for each job by referring to the Alphabetical Cross Index Of Jobs mentioned above.
    While most of the state albums contain jobs for that state alone, there are some exceptions within the Michigan albums. The Irving Powerhouse and Dam album contains the Inks Dam in Texas, the Elk Rapids album contains the Nashua Dam in Iowa, and the Miscellaneous Michigan Sites album contains one site in Sheboygan, Wisconsin as well as multiple Michigan sites.
    The Visual Materials subseries also includes seven glass plate negatives (unidentified), four multiple-site photograph albums, a single unidentified site in a post album, two folders of loose photograph album pages (Michigan and non-Michigan sites), and three folder of individual photographs (labeled Michigan, non-Michigan, and unidentified work sites).
    - Photograph Albums of Connecticut Job Sites
      - Norwich Water Plant, Shetucket River, Job No. W-593 1926-1927 (Box 1)
      - [Scotland Dam, Shetucket River], Uncas [Power Company] [W-17] 1906 (Box 1)
    - Photograph Albums of Iowa Job Sites
      - Cedar Rapids, Cedar River, Job No. W-142, Hydro-Electric Plant 1915-1917 (Box 1)
      - Mitchell Development, Cedar River, Job No. W-484 1922-1926 (Box 1)
      - Waterloo Dam, Ohio River, Job No. W-481-G 1922-1923 (Box 1)
    - Photograph Albums of Michigan Job Sites
      - Alcona [Dam] #1, AuSable River near Bamfield Job No. W-42 1917-1923 (Box 1)
      - Battle Creek Steam Plant, Job No. S-88-J,N, and L 1917, 1920, 1921 (Box 1)
      - Consumers Power Company Work in Michigan designed by Fargo July, 1920 (Box 1)
      - Cooke Dam, AuSable River, Job No. [W-26] 1910-1912 (Box 1)
      - County Line Development, Manistee River, Job No. W-258-E 1924-1925
        - Job site, 2 albums (Box 1)
        - Job site, 3 albums
          - Vol. I, nos. D-1-A to D-121-A (Box 2)
          - Vol. II, nos. D-1-B to D-125-B (Box 2)
          - Vol. III, nos. D-1-C to D-99-C (Box 2)
      - Croton Dam, Muskegon River near Newago, Job No. W-201 1906-1928 (Box 2)
      - Elk Rapids, Job No. W-272 1915-1916 and Nashua [Dam], Cedar River, Iowa, Job No. W-317, 1916-1917 (Box 2)
      - Five Channels, AuSable River, Job No. [W-66] 1911-1913 (Box 2)
      - Foote Dam, AuSable River, Job No. W-238 1916-1918 (Box 2)
      - Irving [Powerhouse and Dam], Thornapple River, Job No. [W-687] 1938-1940, 1942-1943 and Arnold (Inks) Dam, Colorado River, Texas Job No. [W-680] 1936-1937 (Box 2)
      - Jackson Sewage Disposal Plant, Job No. [S.D. 667] 1935-1936 (Box 3)
      - Junction Dam, Manistee River, Job No. W-54-E 1916-1918 (Box 3)
      - Loud Site Dam, AuSable River, Job No. [W-219] 1913 (Box 3)
      - Mio Dam, AuSable River, Job No. W-273 1914-1917 and Plainwell Dam, Kalamazoo River, Job No. W-20-F, 1919 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous sites (mainly Michigan), including:
        - Sheffield Car Company Development, [at Three Rivers], Job No. [W-120] 1916 (Box 3)
        - Sheboygan, WI., Job No. S-341 1917 (Box 3)
        - Peninsular Paper Company, Ypsilanti, Job No. W-113-F 1918 (Box 3)
        - Hamilton Dam and Bridge, Flint, Job No. [W-426] 1920-1921 (Box 3)
        - Barneston Dam, Job No. W-400-F 1919 (Box 3)
        - Charlotte Coal Trestle, Job No. M-399-F 1920 (Box 3)
        - Kalamazoo Coal Trestle, Job No. S-400 1919 (Box 3)
      - Rogers Dam, Muskegon River, Job No. W-89-F 1905, 1922, 1928 (Box 3)
      - Stronach Dam, Manistee River, Job No. W-53 1911-1912, 1915 (Box 3)
      - Webber Dam, Grand River, Job No. [W-7] 1906-1907 (Box 3)
    - Photograph Albums of Nebraska Job Sites
      - Central Nebraska Public Power Photographs of Construction on North Platte River, Job No. W-676 1937, 1939 (Box 3)
      - Fullerton, Cedar River, Job No. C-407-F 1919, 1922-1923 (Box 3)
    - Photograph Albums of Texas Job Sites
      - Hamilton Dam, Flint River at Hamilton, Texas, Job No. W-636 1930-1932 (Box 4)
      - Several Texas Sites, Guadalupe River, Job No. W-604, W-606 1930-1932, 1942 (Box 4)
      - Texas Power Corporation
        - Sequin, Job No. W-568, General, July 3-4 1932 (Flood) (Box 4)
        - Dev. No. 1, Guadalupe River, Job No. W-568
          - Canal 1927-1928 (Box 4)
          - Power House 1926-1928 (Box 4)
          - Spillway 1926-1927 and Flood of July 3-4, 1932 (Box 4)
        - Dev. No. 3, Guadalupe River, Job No. W-568
          - 1927-1928 (Box 4)
          - Spillway 1926-1929 (Box 4)
        - Dev. No. 5, Guadalupe River, Job No. W-568
          - Canal 1926-1927 (Box 4)
          - Power House 1926-1928 (Box 4)
          - Spillway 1926-1928 (Box 4)
    - Photograph Albums of Wisconsin Job Sites
      - Dairyland Dam Site, Flambeau River, Job No. [W-726], 4 albums
        - vol. 1 1949 (photos 1-189) (Box 5)
        - vol. 2 1949-1950 (photos 190-382) (Box 5)
        - vol. 3 1950-1951 (photos 383-579 and bridges no. B11-B19) (Box 5)
        - vol. 4 1951-1952 (photos 580-660 and loose photos and negatives) (Box 5)
      - Jim Falls, Chippewa River, Job No. W-310-L,M,N, 2 albums
        - vol. I 1913-1916, 1922-1923 (Box 5)
        - vol. II 1923-1924 (Box 5)
      - LaCrosse Steam Plant, Job No. S-[2]91 1915 (Box 5)
      - Wissota (vol. II), Chippewa River, Job No. W-305 1916-1919 (Box 5)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, unidentified 12/5/1905, 7 negatives (Box 6)
    - Multiple Site Photograph Albums
      - Bridges (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous Photographs, 2 albums (Box 6)
      - Some Completed Work by Fargo Engineering Co. (Box 6)
      - Transmission Towers (Box 6)
    - Unidentified Site in Post Album 1912-1913
      - Michigan Job Sites, 44 pages (Box 7)
      - Non-Michigan Job Sites, 11 pages (Box 7)
    - Photographs, 3 folders
      - Michigan Job Sites (Box 7)
      - Non-Michigan Job Sites (Box 7)
      - Unidentified Sites (Box 7)
  - Design Reports And Site Specific Materials
    The Design Reports And Site Specific Materials subseries (1.5 linear feet) contains thirty-two folders of design and consulting reports, field notes, correspondence and other material related to various Fargo job sites. The folders are arranged numerically by Fargo job number.
    - M-25-Flat Rock, MI., Test Report 4/23/1923 (Box 7)
    - W-299-E Raisin River, Mi. Reports 1 and 2 on Hydroelectric Projects at Petersburg and Raisinville, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - W-320-St. Cloud, MN, Correspondence, Bound Report, 2 folders (Box 7)
      (includes blueprints and photographs)
    - W-321-Grand Rapids, Mi. East Side Water Power Co. Legal Briefs and Hearing Notes, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - W-322-Ideal Washed Gravel Co. Dayton, OH., Field Notes (Box 7)
    - W-324-Cumberland County Power & Light, Philadelphia, PA., Field Notes (Box 7)
    - W-325-Cornell Dam Project Reports, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - M-326-Correspondence (Box 8)
    - M-327-Reports (Box 8)
    - W-329-Reports, Field Notes (Box 8)
    - W-330-Field Notes (Box 8)
    - W-334-Report (Box 8)
    - W-335-Reports and Preliminary Draft of [original] Building Code for City of Jackson, MI. 2/1916, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - W-336-Report (Box 8)
    - W-337-Report (Box 8)
    - W-338-Report (Box 8)
    - W-339-Correspondence (Box 8)
    - W-341-Field Notes (Box 8)
    - W-342-Report (Box 8)
    - M-343-Field Notes (Box 8)
    - M-343-Misc. I and II, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - W-343-Field Notes-Vol. 4 and 5, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - W-344-Wausau Hydroelectric Plant, Wisconsin River, Notes and estimate (Box 8)
    - W-345-I Bill Cross Development, Wisconsin River, Notes and Estimate (Box 8)
  - Engineering Field Notes
    The Engineering Field Notes subseries (2.7 linear feet) is divided into two sub-subseries of small bound volumes: 25 survey books and miscellaneous notes (each volume approximately 4 x 8 x 1/2 in.). Each sub-subseries is arranged according to the original Fargo call number stamped on each book. An associated site name, Fargo job number and surrounding dates for each book has been provided in this finding aid, where possible. The books vary in content, including: topographical survey notes, level books, wage and hour books and general site notes associated with Fargo construction sites. The books were produced by the head and surveying engineers on each site. Some books contain: photographs, blueprints, maps, indexes and references to photographs found in associated albums in this collection. Therefore, a researcher using a particular album or researching a particular site is advised to search for associated field notes in the list provided herein.
    - 86-Uncas Power Company, [W-17] 4/1908 (Box 9)
    - 87-Cedar Rapids, Iowa 8/1908-9/1908 (Box 9)
    - 88-Belding, [W-127] 6/1909-11/1920 (Box 9)
    - 89-Survey Notes Monticello, IA, [W-63] 11/1909 Decorah, IA and Gravois, MO., 5/1911 (Box 9)
    - 91-Detroit, MI, Reinforced Concrete Pipe Company, [M-77] 6/1909 (Box 9)
    - 298-Thunder Bay River, [W-189] 10/1913 (Box 9)
    - 301-Hamlin Lake, [W-190] 12/1917 (Box 9)
    - 310-Dundee, MI, W-251 5/1913-11/1916 (Box 9)
    - 353-Chippewa River, WI, W-159 8/1913 (Box 9)
    - 354-Three Rivers, MI, Power House 9/1913-12/1913 (Box 9)
    - 355-Grunville 5/1914-6/1914 (Box 9)
    - 454-Menomonie, WI, Red Cedar River 5/1915-8/1915 (Box 9)
    - 557-Trappe and Bill Cross Basins Topological Surveys (cont. from 556), W-345-I 6/1917 (Box 9)
    - 558-Trappe and Bill Cross Basins Topological Surveys (cont. from 557), W-345-I 6/1917 (Box 9)
    - 559-Sheboygan, WI, S-341 6/1917-3/1918 (Box 9)
    - 561-Wisconsin River 5/1917-6/1917, 6/1923 (Box 9)
    - 580-Sheboygan, WI, 8th Street Power Plant, Cost of Work (Box 9)
    - 587-Clinton, MI, W-124 9/1917-6/1919 (Box 9)
    - 623-Anamosa Division Transmission Field Notes, Iowa Electric Co. Appraisal, M-142-J 11/1918 (Box 9)
    - 642-Niles, MI 10/1923 (Box 9)
    - 651-Owosso, MI, Topographic Survey of Shiawassee River, W-390 12/1919 (Box 9)
    - 666-Hopog Damsite, High Falls 11/1920 (Box 9)
    - 667-Hubbardston, MI, Laying out Tail Race for Community Power Co., W-404-G 10/1920-6/1922 (Box 9)
    - 678-Traverse City, MI., Pumping Station 1921 (Box 9)
    - 775-Lawrence, KS, W-381 6/1924-7/1924 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 83 small bound volumes of varying size
    - 11-Guadelupe Water Power Company, Sequin, TX., Level Book 6/1912-4/1913 (Box 9)
    - 132-S-31 12/1910 (Box 9)
      (p. 31-35 only)
    - 134-Site unknown, Level Book December 1908-1909 (Box 9)
    - 136-Norwich, CN., Uncas Development (on Shetuckel River near Norwich) 1907-1909 (Box 9)
    - 138-Sites including Brooklyn Dam and Marsh Farm 1894-1912 (Box 9)
    - 157-South Bend Electric Company, IN. (p.11 and 13 only), W-165 1/1907 (Box 9)
    - 159-Allegan County, MI. Timber Levels, and Jackson County, MI. Catch Basins, Level Book L-19 1/1898-12/1899 (Box 9)
    - 173-[Multiple Michigan Sites] 1906-1908 (Box 9)
    - 174-Marshall, MI. 1905-1920 (Box 9)
    - 191-[Multiple Michigan Sites], Level Book L-51 03/1904-04/1912 (Box 9)
    - 192-St. Joseph River, MI., Level Book L-52 1904 (Box 9)
    - 223-Montague and Turners Falls, MA., W-132 1907-1909 (Box 9)
    - 225-Eau Claire, WI. 1909-1913 (Box 9)
    - 227-Belding, MI. 1906-1913 (Box 9)
    - 287-Turners Falls, Connecticut River 1910 (Box 9)
    - 288-Detroit, MI., Reinforced Concrete Pipe Co., [1909 (Box 9)
    - 289-Detroit, MI., Reinforced Concrete Pipe Co. 1909-1910 (Box 9)
    - 318-Sturgeon River, MI., W-237 10/1912-5/1914 and Lewiston, ME., W-240 (Box 9)
    - 320A-Menomonie Basin Site Notes 1915-1916 (Box 9)
    - 320B-Menomonie Basin Land Line Notes 6/1915-12/1915 (Box 9)
    - 465B-Floyd Site, Iowa, Topography 1915 (Box 9)
    - 574-Kawishiwi River, MN., W-356-G 6/1917 (Box 10)
    - 581-Trappe Development, W-352 6/1917-7/1917 (Box 10)
    - 584-Eaton Rapids, MI. Developments, W-359 8/1917-9/1918 (Box 10)
    - 597-M-401 5/1918 (Box 10)
    - 598-Kent, OH., W-378, Water Supply Investigation 1918 (Box 10)
    - 600-Davis Dam, Chippeawa Falls, WI. 01/11/1918 (Box 10)
    - 601-Chippewa River, WI., Preliminary Survey to Locate Proposed Dam Site on the East Branch 1/1918 (Box 10)
      (includes map)
    - 602-Water Power in Wisconsin, W-370 1918 (Box 10)
    - 603-Eau Claire, WI., Dells Paper and Pulp Co., W-305-J 1918 (Box 10)
    - 605-Ypsilanti, MI. Peninsular Paper Co. and Oak Knitting Co., W-113-f and W-375 1918 (Box 10)
    - 607-LaCrosse, WI., S-291 1915 (Box 10)
    - 608-Cedar River, IA., W-317 1918 (Box 10)
    - 609-St. Joseph River 1918 (Box 10)
    - 610-Eddy Paper Company, White Pigeon, MI. 5/21/1918 (Box 10)
    - 611A-Diaries of Four Engineers, indexed 6/1916-4/1918 (Box 10)
    - 612-Miscellaneous Sites including Paint Creek Basin, Stilson Creek, Yellow River, Contour Is., binding missing (Box 10)
    - 613-Paint Creek Basin, Land Line Notes 8/1915-10/1915 (Box 10)
    - 615-East Jordan, MI., Jordan River, Investigation of possible dam sites, W-372-F 5/1918 (Box 10)
    - 616-Grand River, MI.(near Painesville) 7/1918 (Box 10)
    - 617-Hamilton, Ohio, Miami River, W-382 7/1918 (Box 10)
    - 624-Cornell Dam, WI., W-325 6/1916-8/1916 (Box 10)
    - 625-Cornell Dam, WI. (book 2 of 2), W-325 6/1916-11/1916 (Box 10)
    - 626-Coal Trestle at Charlotte, MI. 11/1918-2/1920 (Box 10)
    - 627-Carson City, MI., Survey of Fish Creek, W-404 2/1919-5/1920 (Box 10)
    - 628-Saco River, ME., Levels, W-394 2/1919 (Box 10)
    - 630-Iowa Electric Co., M-142-J, Notes on Generating Stations and Equipment 11/1918-1/1919 (Box 10)
    - 637-Kalamazoo State Hospital Concrete Trestle, S-410 6/1919-7/1919 (Box 10)
    - 638-Briscoe Motor Corp. (near Jackson, MI.), F-405, Storage Tank 3/1919 (Box 10)
    - 640-Lawton, MI., Paw Paw Creek, W-417, Survey notes 04/22/1919-04/25/1919 (Box 10)
      (includes correspondence to head engineer and village of Lawton)
    - 641-Notes on Fargo Engineering Clients, W-417 undated (Box 10)
    - 644-Jackson, MI., Topographic Survey of Dr. Flinton and Cowham Estates, M-141-K and W-141-L 5/1919-6/1919 (Box 10)
    - 645-Cement City, MI., Town Improvements, M-420 11/1919-2/1920 (Box 10)
    - 646-Litchfield, MI, Kalamazoo River, W-423 9/1917 (Box 10)
      (includes blueprint)
    - 647-Wilson Mill Site, Milan, MI. 7/1919 (Box 10)
    - 648-Vanderbuilt, MI., Sturgeon River, Yuill Bros. Dams, W-418 and W-457 07/30/1919 (Box 10)
    - 650-Flint, MI., W-426 9/22/1919 (Box 10)
    - 670-Traverse City, MI., W-460 2/1921-5/1921 (Box 10)
    - 671-Kiddville, MI., Traverse up Flat River above Belding, W-462 01/17/1921 (Box 10)
    - 672-Charlotte, MI. Charlotte Gas Co. Coal Trestle, M-399 undated (Box 10)
    - 673-Black River, M-300 undated (Box 10)
    - 674-St Joseph River, W-401-F 12/1920 (Box 10)
    - 687-Jim Falls, WI., W-310, Topography and Misc. Data, and Cornell Dam, WI., W-325, Levels 9/1915 (Box 10)
    - 732-1-Paint Creek, US Land Notes (Book one of two) undated (Box 10)
    - 735-1-Jim Falls, WI., W-305, Notes on Drilling 11/1916-5/1917 (Box 10)
    - 736-2-Jim Falls, WI., W-305, (cont. from Book 735-1?) 1916 (Box 10)
    - 757-St. Edwards, NB., W-552, and Milford, NB., W-554 Undated (Box 10)
    - 763-Vicinity of Stuyvesant Falls Dam, W-567 4/1924-5/1924 (Box 10)
    - 764-Middleton, OH., Miami River, W-565, Levels and Topography of Woodsdale Dam 1923 (Box 10)
    - 767-Elkhardt, IN., W-579, Notes on Headgates and American Coating Co. Mill 1924 (Box 10)
    - 768-W-489 1918 (Box 10)
    - 770-Milford, NB., w-554 undated (Box 10)
    - 782-Gratz Mill, W-475 11/7/1921 (Box 10)
    - 784-Wissota, WI., W-305, Wage and Hour Book 11/1915-3/1916 (Box 10)